<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Frame &amp; Wall DeconSwap</Name>
  <Author>Tallinu</Author>
  <Version>1.2.1</Version>
  <Description>[h1]Frame &amp; Wall DeconSwap[/h1]
Reduce the chance of hull breaches and improve tool usage consistency by swapping the use of the wrench and grinder for deconstructing certain build states of frames, walls, and landing pads. The time to grind open an airtight frame is also slightly increased, from 0.5 to 0.75 second.
Requires [b]BepInEx[/b] and [b]StationeersLaunchPad[/b].
[i]The changes made by this mod are not retained in your save games, so you can freely try it and remove it.[/i]
[h2]Why bother? Why these tools?[/h2]
"Unwelding" a sealed frame with a wrench is way too easy to do accidentally while working on your plumbing, causing dangerous hull breaches! (You've never had that happen, or nearly happen? Play long enough, and it will.) And a wrench isn't even an appropriate tool for a [i]weld-cutting[/i] job.
Meanwhile, the initial placement of frames, walls, and landing pads, which you perform with your bare hands, requires a grinder and battery charge to undo -- even though most other construction tasks that are reversed by a grinder are [i]welding operations[/i].
This mod increases safety and tool usage consistency by editing some build states of frames, walls, and landing pads, swapping the use of wrench and grinder around so that frame and pad welding steps are undone with the grinder, and the initial placement stages are picked up easily with the wrench. The time required to grind open the final, airtight stage of a frame is also slightly increased to help prevent accidents.
In terms of game balance, you'll use more grinder charge for dismantling fully welded frames, but won't need it for walls, and most landing pad pieces still require the same operations, just in reverse order. Seems close enough to me, and well worth the benefits.
With DeconSwap, dismantling pipes won't vent your base if you misclick, twitch, or hold the button a moment too long.
</Description>
  <ChangeLog xsi:nil="true" />
  <WorkshopHandle>3545236535</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags />
  <Dependencies />
  <LoadBefore />
  <LoadAfter />
  <InGameDescription xsi:nil="true" />
</ModMetadata>